Now, the goal of this model is to train it so that it can take in
我们的目标是训练该模型
one character and produce a next character and that's what this next step,
使其能够接受一个字符并预测出下个字符
Making Predictions is all about.
下一步“做出预测”将讲解这方面的知识
We basically want to create functions that can take in
我们需要创建函数
a character and have our network predict the next character.
该函数能够接受一个字符并使网络预测下个字符
Then, we want to take that character,
然后再将该字符放入网络中
pass it back in, and get more and more predicted next characters.
并预测更多的下个字符
We'll keep doing this until we generate a bunch of text.
直到生成大量文本
So, you've been given this predict function which will help with this.
我们提供了这个 predict 函数
This function takes in a model and
此函数接受一个模型和当前字符
occurring character and its job is to basically give us
它的职责是
back the encoded value of
返回下个预测字符的编码值
the predictive next character and the hidden state that's produced by our model.
以及模型生成的隐藏状态
So, let's see what it's actually doing step-by-step.
我们逐步了解下该函数
It's taking in our input character and converting it into it's encoded integer value.
它会接受输入字符并将其转换为编码整数值
Then, as part of pre-processing,
在预处理过程中
we're turning that into
我们将该值变成
a one-hot encoded representation and then converting these inputs into a tensor.
独热编码表示法 并将这些输入转换为张量
These inputs we can then pass to our model,
然后就可以将这些输入传入模型中
and then you'll see a couple of steps that are really
下面的几步
similar to what we saw in our training loop.
与训练循环中的步骤很相似
We put our inputs on a GPU if it's
如果有 GPU 则将输入移到 GPU 上
available and we detach our hidden state from its history here.
在这里使隐藏状态与其历史记录分离
Then, we pass in the inputs and the hidden state to
将输入和隐藏状态传入模型中
our model which returns an output and a new hidden state.
返回一个输出和新的隐藏状态
Next, we're processing the output a little more.
接下来 继续处理该输出
We're applying a softmax function to get p probabilities for the likely next character.
应用 softmax 函数以获得下个潜在字符的概率 p
So, p is a probability distribution over
p 是给定输入字符 x 后
all the possible mixed characters given the input character x.
所有潜在下个字符的概率分布
Now, we can generate more sensible characters by
我们可以通过仅考虑前 k 个潜在字符
only considering the k most probable characters.
生成更合理的字符
So, here we're giving you a couple of lines of code to use top k sampling,
这几行代码是 top_k 抽样代码
which finds us the k most likely next characters.
可以帮助我们查找前 k 个最有可能的下个字符
Then, here we're adding an element of randomness,
在这里引入随机性
something that selects from among those top likely next characters.
从这些前 k 个下个字符中选择字符
So, then we have a most likely next character and we're actually returning
选择最有可能的下个字符
the encoded value of that character and the hidden state produced by our model,
并返回该字符的编码值和模型生成的隐藏状态
but we'll basically want to call the predict function several times,
我们需要多次调用 predict 函数
generating one character's output,
生成一个字符的输出
then passing that in as input and predicting the next and next characters.
将该输出当做输入传入模型中并预测下个字符、下下个字符等
That brings me to our next function sample.
这就要提到下个函数 sample 了
Sample will take in our trained model and the size of text that we want to generate.
sample 的参数是训练过的模型、要生成的文本大小
It will also take in prime,
还有 prime
which is going to be a set of characters that we want to start our model off with.
prime 是一组帮助模型开始构建文本的字符
Lastly, we will take in a value for top k which will
最后一个参数是 top_k
just return our k most probable characters in our predict function.
返回 predict 函数中的前 k 个字符
So, in here, we're starting off by moving our model to GPU if it's available,
首先在这里将模型移到 GPU 上（如果有 GPU 的话）
and here we're also initializing the hidden state with a batch size of one because,
并用批次大小 1 初始化隐藏状态
for one character that we're inputting at a time,
因为我们一次输入一个字符
the batch size will be one.
因此批次大小将为 1
In this way, prediction is quite different than training a model.
这么看来 预测和训练模型截然不同
Then, you'll see that we're getting each character in our prime word.
然后获取 prime 单词中的每个字符
The prime word basically helps us answer the question,
prime 单词可以告诉我们
how do we start to generate text?
如何开始生成文本
We shouldn't just start out randomly.
我们不能随机地开始
So, what is usually done is to provide a prime word or a set of characters.
因此通常会提供一个 prime 单词或一组字符
Here the default prime set is just the,
我们传入的 prime 单词是 The
T-H-E, but you can pass in any set of characters that you want as the prime.
但是你可以传入任何一组字符
The sample function first processes
sample 函数首先按顺序处理这些字符
these characters in sequence adding them to a list of characters.
将它们添加到字符列表中
It then calls predict on these characters passing in our model,
然后对这些字符调用 predict
each character and hidden state and this returns
传入模型、每个字符以及隐藏状态
the next character after our prime sequence and the hidden state.
返回 prime 序列后的下个字符和隐藏状态
So, here we have all our prime characters in the default case.
这些是 prime 字符
This is going to be T, H,
即 T、h、e
and E and then we're going to append the next most likely character.
然后附加下个最有可能的字符
So, we're basically building up a list of characters here,
在这里形成一个字符列表
then we're going to generate more and more characters.
然后生成越来越多的字符
In this loop, we're passing in our model and the last character in our character list.
在此循环里 传入模型和字符列表里的最后一个字符
This returns the next character and the hidden state.
返回下个字符和隐藏状态
This character is appended to our list and the cycle starts all over again.
将此字符附加到列表上并重新开始此循环
So, predict is generating a next likely character which is
predict 生成下个潜在字符
appended to our list and then that goes back as input into our predict function.
将此字符附加到列表上并作为输入传入 predict 函数中
The effect is that we're getting next and next and
这样我们就能获取下个字符、下下个字符等
next characters and adding them to our characters list,
并将它们添加到字符列表中
that is until we reach our desired text length.
直到达到期望的文本长度
Finally, we join all these characters together to return a sample text,
最后 将这些字符连接到一起并返回示例文本
and here I've generated a couple samples.
我生成了几个示例文本
You can see that I've passed in my model that was trained for 20 epochs, and I said,
传入训练 20 个周期的模型
generate a text that's 1,000 characters long starting with the prime word Anna.
生成长 1000 个字符的文本并以 prime 单词 Anna 开头
I've also passed in a value for top k equal to five.
top_k 的值设为 5
You can see that this starts with the prime word and generates
可以看到 示例文本以 prime 单词开头
what might be thought of as a paragraph of text in a book.
生成了一个小说段落
Even with just a few prime characters,
即使只有几个 prime 字符
our model is definitely making complete and real words that make sense.
模型也能够生成完整的真实单词并且比较合理
The structure and spelling looks pretty good
结构和拼写看起来很棒
even if the content itself is a little confusing,
虽然内容本身很奇怪
and here's another example where I've loaded in a model by
这是另一个示例 我根据名称传入了一个模型
name and I'm using this loaded model to generate a longer piece of text,
并用此模型生成了更长的文本
starting with the prime words, "And Levin said."
以 prime 单词“And Levin said”开头
So, this is pretty cool.
很酷
A well-trained model can actually generate some text that makes some sense.
训练良好的模型能够生成比较合理的文本
It learned just from looking at long sequences of
模型通过查看很长的字符序列
characters what characters were likely to come next.
预测下个字符可能是什么
Then in our sampling and prediction code,
在我们的抽样和预测代码中
we used top-k sampling and some randomness in selecting the best likely next character.
我们利用 top-k 抽样和随机性选择下个最有可能的字符
You can train a model like this on any other text data.
你可以使用任何其他文本数据训练模型
For example, you could try it on generating
例如 你可以用它尝试生成
Shakespeare sonnets or another text of your choice.
莎士比亚十四行诗或其他文本
Great job on getting this far.
很棒 你已经学习了很多知识
You've really learned a lot about implementing RNNs in PyTorch.
知道如何在 PyTorch 中实现 RNN 了